Ciao, I'm Clippo and today we are going to see how the canaliser can be used in order to perform several actions.
For example, this tool can allow us to go through an analysis and also a stimulation of a bus communication system.
As you know, the bus communication systems are widely used in the automotive sector because they are basically mandatory means that are used to communicate between electronic control units.
There are several types of bus communication systems. The main ones, for example, are CAM protocol communication, the Lean one, FlexRay and several others.
I suggest you, if you did not do that before, to go through the CAM protocol lesson because it will be very useful for you.
And it contains a lot of mandatory information in order to better understand this canaliser lesson.
So, first of all, the screen that you are just looking at is the main page of the already prepared canaliser configuration.
As we were telling before, canaliser can be used in order to check, for example, if there is a communication between several TCUs in a bus communication system.
And also, in case of a positive response or a communication ongoing, it will allow you to perform also an analysis and a study of the kind of communication and any issue of the communication itself.
On the other hand, canaliser will allow you to collect data, so perform and acquire data from the communication itself.
In order to get started, let's open a new configuration.
We will have the opportunity to start from the basics.
So, let's go here, new.
Let's open up the default one.
Click on create configuration.
And the window that you will see open would be something like that.
We are in the phrase layer.
You will understand later what it is.
So, let's move to the configuration layer.
And here you've got one of the most important window of canaliser tool, which is the measurement setup window.
As you can see, there are several blocks here with different names and that can be used in order to perform several things.
First of all, there is this block here where you see offline and online.
This is the data source where you can find basically if you want to work online or offline.
Online means basically that you are currently using a cam case and canaliser connected to a specific, for example, cam communication bus.
And you are looking at the cam communication in real life.
So, the communication is ongoing while we are looking at it and we are analyzing it.
On the other side, what we can do is work in offline mode.
So, if you double click here, as you can see, these two blocks here just turn gray and we enable this folder here.
Now we are in offline mode, which means that we can, for example, but we will see this later.
We can start from a already acquired log.
So, already collected the information from a cam communication, which happened in the past and from where we acquired the data.
And we can review that offline.
So basically just using our PC, we do not need to be physically, for example, connected to cam communication system, the cam bus.
So these are the two main modes of operation that we can go through and we can use to canaliser.
There are here several other blocks that can be used.
Statistics ones, trace, data, graphics, logging.
We will dive deeper into those in the next minutes.
So, don't worry for now.
But apart from the operational mode that we can use canaliser for.
There are also analysis windows.
For example, in online mode, we can insert an interactive generator blocks.
To set the cam communication itself.
A program node to use, for example, cable programs.
So basically codes that are written by ourselves and that can be used in order to perform several stimulations of the cam communication.
We can insert filters of different kinds.
Channel filters.
So filtering by specific cam communication channels.
Or we can add event and variables filters.
To have a closer look at specific things that we want to look at.
And in online mode, as you can see, we can, for example, here enable the logging block.
And this is the way we can use in order to collect data.
And that can be done and reviewed in offline mode.
So, let's move to the first things, the most important ones, in order to configure our canaliser setup.
First of all, we need to understand here, on top, the hardware layer.
We need to set up the hardware configuration that we are currently using.
For this lesson, we will use a lot that was acquired in the program that I'm working with.
And basically here, on channel usage, the log was performed acquiring only one cam bus communication.
So here on cam, we need to select one.
I did not acquire any link communication in the log that we will use.
So we select here zero.
And select OK.
As you can see, in this right window here, the system is telling us that all channel specific options are OK.
So we can move on.
In particular, we have here top left channel mapping.
So here what we can do, we can basically link on the application channel column here, the virtual can channel.
And that canaliser will use for its operations.
With the hardware column link.
Which is basically the real channel of the can case that is physically connected to the computer, to the PC that we are using in order to run canaliser.
For example, right now, this window, among all the choices, you see that under transceiver column, we've got only virtual can channels.
And that's because right now I do not have any can case connected to my PC.
So canaliser allows us to perform any kind of operations that we want, but it's telling us that we do not have any real and physical can case connected to the PC.
And so we can just use virtual channels, but that is enough for our demonstration of canaliser usage.
So let's click OK and let's use the virtual can channel 1 to the virtual can bus 1.
Now we've got to configure the kind of can bus communication that we want to review in offline mode.
I acquired a log from the program, as I was telling before, that I will work on.
And specifically, this is a program with a network topology equal to Atlantis side can have the communication, which is basically flexible data rate and protocol.
Which means that, for example, here, as you can see, can 1.
This is the same virtual can channel that we just configured on channel mapping.
But as you can see here, cam controller mode, we cannot use cam with a baud rate up to 500 kg baud.
But we need to select this window ISOCAMFD flexible data rate.
And as you can see, the data rate field just appears because, as you can understand from the cam protocol lesson, cam flexible data rate communication differs from the standard cam communication.
So let's now go ahead and choose six分 box,fal file method that we coffee discussed.
So let's select how to load our weights achieve this calculation, how to load our weights in camp and unmute it and get we are having them aside to pouring spikes.
We must give you we 5출 the probability of swine output into it.
Back to this values at 9 Ginger pole parameter.
This is the second value procedure.
And the way we just substitute what we prepared to do, we make it a while going to increase ourploy Polar,
so it's actually highly strategic data set-up時間.
So I really ON questions, I'll continue to ensure that we wanted this one.
soon as we set up correctly the data rate okay and what we can do now is for
example adding here in offline mode the source that we want to use for our
activities in particular as I told you before we will use an already acquired log so we click here
add offline source my source is here a blf file so binary logging file
and as you can see now that we add this offline source the one that we just selected it appears
also here in the measurement setup window just above the folder where we double click
if you guys have got a log for example in a different file which can be
i don't know a national file in order to perform this offline analysis of the data you need to
convert it to a blf so what you need to do is very useful on this side as well you can go here on
tools login file conversion click here and as you can see there are two fields source file destination
file on source file you need to select the file that you want to convert into a blf file so you can see
file select it and then automatically here analyzer tells you the destination of the file the name of the
file and the format which is dot blf you can change the name you can change the destination wherever you want
for example here try at the end of the name save save and you just need to wait for the analyzer conversion
of the file as you can see here there is a percentage and as soon as it goes up to 100 you have your file
converted to a blf one let's just wait for it to finish but we have already uploaded here a blf file so we are good to go
okay let's close here
before moving to the analysis windows the trace one data graphics and so on let's see another very
very useful feature that analyzer provides to us which is on tools top left can db plus plus editor
open it as you can see
this window here on this bottom allows you to open or even create a new dbc file database scan file
that let's add example this dbc file that will be needed for us to review the log that we want to use for this demonstration
and here as you can see there is the old dbc file that we just uploaded vector can db plus plus editor allows
you not only to create dbc files but also to add new messages new network nodes and you can signals
into the already existing and this is the case dbc file for example we can click on here network nodes new
and we can add this window here the name of our node that we are just creating so try node we need to
give it the hexadecimal address let's use one two three
and now we can create and now we can for example proceed creating a new message among the list of all
already existing can messages so let's click on the right button of the mouse messages new message let's call it
try message id id 2.4 dlc data land code 8 it's fine and we can click ok so i'm on the list of messages here
where we can reduce and expand if we search for
try message here it is we'll find it here so we can click click with the right button and message
transmitter as you can see we create a new message but we did not set up yet which is the vcu
and this can buzz that is transmitting this message so you can for example click on here transmitter layer
add add and you can select the ecu in the this dbc because it's transmitting the new message that we created
so we select the try node that we just created
and we click ok the same goes for a signal if we want to create a can signal inside
messages messages that we just created right button new and the process is
pretty much the same one for that we go through and went through for the node creation and account message creation
we can select here for example by order value type sign sign load double unit or scaling factor offset minimum maximum
and what we need to do for example in such a scenario we need to
link to link this signal to the can message that contains the signal itself so on the signal we go on messages
add we need to select from all the can messages
this message that we just created try this so okay
and here it goes
can db plus plus editor is very useful in order to not only create but also to modify existing dbc database
we can as you just saw we can find transmission and reception relationships we can adjust can signals
position inside the can message and so on let's go back to the
main canalizer window measurement setup window
as a canalizer user you will be able to analyze the bus communication depending from
the kind of communication so if it is a can if it is based on can protocol link protocol flex ray and so on
but there are a lot of
windows that will support you in your
analysis and in your
work
which are
the ones that we just mentioned before so let's go through them one by one
just to complete our basic setup configuration so we
configure the hardware side
we configure the offline source that we want to use for our demonstration a very important thing to do
right now is adding here on analysis stimulation
clicking on database management there can dbc that
we need to link
to the virtual can channel that we are using in order to review the log that we acquire and that we are
reviewing right now that's because otherwise we will not be able to recognize the can messages that are inside the log that we are reviewing
because
canalizer in order to correctly recognize the can messages needs a sort of let me say
and communication translator which is the can dbc according to a specific can message id
for example
canalizer will be able to recognize the message itself and so for example recognize which are the can signals inside the can message
which are those positions inside the can message so
analyzer will be able to convert the can signals values and so on but analyzer needs a source in order to
mapping a translator in order to perform all these actions and that is the dbc so on can channel one which is the one that we are
configured
we click with the right button add database and
and then we select the dbc that we firstly used in order to acquire the logo we are reviewing
and as you can see we just added for the channel one this dbc
here canalizer tells you the file name and the path where the file was extracted from
so first window that we are going to look at is trace window
as you can see on the trace layer bottom left there is already an already open trace window but
we can close it for example and we can insert it again and analyze the stimulation
clicking here on trace view trace and here it is
if we want to run the
simulation so review the already acquired data
on this file here we can go on trace and click on the top left button here start
as you can see there is a time reference here that is running a channel
here cam5 id this is the example id of this cam frame this is the data field
of this cam frame the one the method the one with id 119 but as you can see under name there isn't anything
and that's because we are using here on channel mapping the virtual cam channel one
while as you can see when this log was acquired it used channel cam5 so first of all
if it happens to you to be in this same scenario we need to go back here in the
measurement setup window right click here on the folder where we uploaded
the log that we want to review offline mode configuration
on the channel mapping layer here click add new set bus type
we are reviewing our can communication bus data so can source channel so basically what we need to do
one remember from the trace here just we need to re-address all the messages that were acquired on cam5
we need to re-map them to this nation channel one because this is the one that we are currently
used in order for the data so we just created a new channel mapping set called channel mapping set one
but we need we can also rename it but it doesn't matter this channel mapping setup will take all those
messages from cam5 source channel and we will remap them to the cam channel one let's click okay
right button again offline file list this is the file currently uploaded channel mapping here known
but we need to use the one that we just created we select it close it back to source
and we're on the log as you can see now
the channel the channel that is being recognized for all those can messages that were transmitted at
these time stamps here through all the log are now seen coming from can one and as you can see here
we are recognizing also the can message name because right now we are using correctly both the can
channel and also the can database so as you can see here the trace window allows you to basically look at
the transmission and reception of all the cam messages inside for example this offline log but that can be
be done as well on the other hand in online mode while for example performing an operation called sniffing which is
basically a passive listening of the campaign communication in real time and
you can perform several actions here for example on the trace window you can
have a detailed view of the communication so i'm selecting one message here you can see
which is the time stamp that was
acquired the direction ex
the name of the cam messages with this nid
the channel that it went through dlc.9 code the data field in extra decimal values byte per byte
and also the list of all the cam signals inside the cam message and the values that they've got at that time
that the message was sent you can have a similar signal value description here
for example just clicking expanding the cam message here on the left plus and here it is
basically those can signal values are the same ones that are present here on the data field
here in the decimal values which is this report here but the canalizer is converting
these data field according to the dbc that we associate to the scan channel so basically canalizer is taking
these data field in decimal values and using the dbc is recognizing the can signal position inside this
cam message and converting them according to the dbc factor offset and minimum and maximum
indications that are recording there you can perform other thing you can for example add some markers here
clicking with the red button on this gray column new markers so for example if you want to associate to this
specific specific time instant and who can message transmission or reception a specific level name
or no level marker try you can also add a comment and have a background color program color program color
you click ok and you have the marker here so just scrolling with the mouse
and pointing at it you will see even marker dry
mark the name and a comment
and you can remove it just
that you can remove it on the other hand if on the top left here you've got the detail view you can
add also statistics view which is a little bit different from the detail view because for example
statistic view we are pointing to a specific message and this those columns here are telling us
for example all the can signals inside that can message but also minimum maximum average value
we can also perform
several other things
for example we can have a difference view
selecting
different signals for example engine have to choose
here at this time stamp but it was also sent
previously or after this time reference
and so we can for example select it from trace window and have a
conversion between the signal values for example
respect to two different time instant and so on
there are other windows very useful for example the graphic window here that you can find when you open
a new configuration on the analysis layer here at the bottom of the main window
but as for the trace window you can go here top left a nice simulation and add a new graphic window just clicking on it
and this is very very useful because it can
can give you a visual reference for example i can signal evolution to in this case a radio parallel
so you can click on this blank column blank section here right button add signals
here we've got basically the whole dbc
that we can create this is the dbc name
so among all the can signals
you can choose whatever you want
but for example we can filter for can messages
so if we know that a specific signal that we are interested in is inside the can message
yes bcm fd9 you can search for the cam message and then we can signal inside of it
or we can also filter by the means so
the bus node that transmits that specific cam framework and signal
let's for example add the vehicle
let's check it and drag it here on the left just click on apply it will appear here okay
and as you can see here we've got its name but we do not have any value yet
and we've got just a whole blank window so what you need to do is run again canalizer top left
and you will see that now it's running to the log and you've got something moving here
so on the y-axis you see the calcium that we have the vehicle speed vso signal
the measuring unit the km per hour while on the x-axis you've got the time
if you want to adjust for example the whole graph according to the whole long time period acquired
you can click here fit x and here you are
you've got the evolution of the vehicle speed can signal to the whole candle as you can see it was
equal to zero for a very long time and then start increasing decreasing and so on so what you can do
is for example adjusting not only the x-axis but also the y-axis in order to have a better understanding
of the value that for example this can signal had during the log but if you want to have further
detail on specific values that you can signal had you can click on here so you can activate the measurement
cursor as you can see the top left a column just here the y one here so if you smooth
the measurement marker that we just added you will see near the cursor that you've got a value
represent of the value of the signal but also the time instant
and so let's move for example here when the vehicle speeds start increasing and you see the reflection
on the top left of the value but also on the marker measurement here axis that we added
if you want to perform a comparison between different time distance you can click here
so you will just activate the difference cursor you can see another column here here and another
measurement marker appeared here the red one so you can move for example marker the difference marker
and as you can see for this marker here you just have not only the value of the signal for that time
reference but also the t1 which is a time distance of course and the dt so the difference
time period between the two measurement markers and if you want to have
the same delta measurement but not for the time references between the two markers but for the
y values so the values of that you can see now between the two different time instances you can refer
to the p y here column so between marker blue marker and red one for example the vehicle speed difference
is equal to 80 kilometers per hour which means that if the blue marker the value of the vehicle speed was
equal to 36 basically meters per hour you've got some to add to it
80 kilometers for a total of 115 and 16 km per hour in order to add the red value the red marker value of the
can signal what you can do here is adding also a lot of several can signals because you can do that not only with this one can signal but basically all of the can signals inside of the dbc that we're using so for example always clicking here with the red button add can signal we can
and i don't know how for example the engine speed
can signal and need to run again
analyzer in order to have
an uploading of an upload of this can signal evolution
and as you can see we just have a
a sort of yellow let me say
value here that goes up and down this is the edge speed the one that we just
added
and the same things can be done with markers
but what you need to do in order to switch from
from a can signal analysis to the other one is selecting the one that you want to
refer to because if we select here the engine speed can signal the markers will tell the value of that can signal
not the vehicle speed for example anymore
so if we want to separate them
we can do that here so
we click on here
show signals in separate diagram
as you can see now
two can signals are splitted in two different
windows with the same
x reference or the same time distance we can again adjust the x axis and
adjust the all and fit all the signals y axis
so
these are some of the most important features on the graphic
window you can zoom in
example with specific term references and
adjust y axis you can
let's go back to the whole log here
you can click on here
which is drag zoom mode so instead of clicking
zooming in or zooming out
by one click at a time
you can click the drag and zoom function
and basically selecting the part of the graphs where you are interested in
and you can move signals up down
but there are a lot of feature here you can undo whatever you just did
and so on
it's very very useful
from a visual point of view
but let's now go back to the main measurement setup window and let's go through for example the
data here window let's double click here
right button add signals let's do that with the same signal that we just used
vehicle speed
and so
sig
fly
and
engine speed
okay they appear here
and what happens for example you see several
columns name value unit row value bar
which is a
sort of
progression bar which shows you
visual
from visual point of view the evolution of the can signal menu
if you run
an evolution of the can signals this is very useful when it is used
for example
while performing online activities so you are connected to a real bus
a real cam bus for example
where there is an ongoing communication between issues and you can have a visual reference for
specific scan signals the one that you are interested in
about the evolution and so on
so
um
basically data window
display as you just see
as you just saw
the values of
can signals or system variables diagnostic parameters
whatever you want in different types of
representation
and
they give you
sort of
graphical overview of those things
there are
other windows for example the can statistics one
as you can see they are all available here
if you want to open them
can statistics
here you've got different informations
for example regarding the bus activity
which can be
can lean
flex ray
whatever they are
during measurement
while operating in online mode or after a measurement
among those information there are as you can see the bus load percentage
the minimum sending in distance in
millisecond
or i don't know frame per bus
cheap state
transceiver errors
standard data
counters
and so on
so if we run again
you will see for example the bus load
here
evolving or the standard data
calculation
and you will also have
not only
an indication of the current and last
values of those information but also
minimum minimum maximum and average value
so
let's move to
another very powerful feature that
analyzer
offers you which is
the diagnostic feature site
you can find it here
tools
on my bed
you see diagnostics here
sorry
here on the top left
so
what we can do here
basically is
analyzing and studying
also the diagnostic communication
according to the several diagnostic protocols
that can be used in the automotive sector
for example
the unified diagnostic services
standard one
or the keyword protocol
so the starting file
that needs to be used
for example
in order to perform this kind of analysis
is the
cdd
diagnostic
and
that can be done
here
adding diagnostic description
you can use basic descriptions
already available in
canadizer
as i
told you
there is already available
the uds or keyword protocol one
but
let's use
these here
let's search for a specific file
since i
i've got the cdb for my
for my program
so
search for it
we select the dot cdd file
canal data diagnostic file
and let's wait for it to be uploaded in canalizer
so as you can see
we just uploaded this file
this is the path
the specific interface that
we've used
and then we've described
for our kind of diagnostic communication
click ok
and then we click on
diagnostic parameters
what we can do here is
adding
a lot of things
for example
that would be
used
mostly
not be used in offline mode
but
it can be used in online mode
in order to interact
for example
with the
ECU under testing
for example
because
as you can see
if we are in offline mode
we cannot
use the diagnostic console
the cold memory here
window and the session control
neither the
OBE2 one
but as soon as
we switch to the online
configuration
even if we are not running
analyzer
and we are not even connected to
a real cam bus
let's just stay
in this configuration setup
just to show you
those windows here
diagnostic console
that
show us
for example
basically
all the information
that are contained
in the cdb file
for example
you've got
here the possibility
to change
the session control
that
the ECU under test
is using
in particular
double clicking here
you can
activate the
programming session
but as you can see
RKS can only be sent
during a running measurement
and now
canalyzer is not running
but even if we start
the measurement here
canalyzer will tell us
that we're missing the licenses
but also there is no
real hardware connected
so it's not useful
to run
services right now
as we
cannot work in an online mode
but
as you can see
we can change
not only the
session control
we can perform
an ECU reset
double clicking
always
we can
for example
here on
engineering parameters
we can
read
or write
write
all the RDIs
and DIDs
that are included
in the
CDD
we can
use the
IO control
commands
in order to
control
manually
actuators
we can run
teams
and so on
we can
for example
look at the
fault memory
here
according to
who we
want to
specifically do
you see here
the commands
the value
that we send
if we want
to run
a specific
command
what we want
to
specific
action
that we
want to perform
but
let me say
for the
full memory
analysis
this
analyzer
provides
you
already
a
value
to
window
the
right
one
to
diagnostic
console
for
memory
you
select
the
CDD
that we
uploaded
and here
you can
basically
have a review
of all the
DTCs that
are
present in the
error memory
for this
specific
ECU under
testing
right now
we cannot
perform
anything
yes we
are not
connected to
a real
ECU under
the loop
but
this is
something that
Catalyzer allows
you to do
and which is
very useful
in case
in the case
of where
you
do not have
the possibility
to use
for example
already
available tools
like
the analyzer
for
media programs
or
CDA
for
enough
programs
on
the other
hand
there is
another
window
that can
be used
the
session
control
as we
saw
in the
diagnostic
console
window
you can
change
session
control
using
a
dedicated
window
here
basically
perform
the same
thing
or you
can
unlock
secure
gateway
and
modify
unlock
security
accesses
RPC
reset
and
and so
on
so
the
diagnostic
side
of
Catalyzer
can be
very useful
as well
along with
all the other
windows
that we
have seen
since
we are
now configured
in online
mode
as I
was
showing you
before
we can
use
canalizer
also to
perform
unlock
so basically
we can
collect
data
starting
from
a
communication
and
we can
do that
enabling
here
so
in online
mode
enabling
here
this
block
login
we double
click on
this folder
we select
the destination
folder
and
the
name
of the
file
that
we want
to generate
and here
the file
format
will have
binary
log file
so
as soon
as you
for example
know
name
sorry
log
and
we do not
need to
change the
destination
folder
since
we will not
perform a
real log
you see
here
the name
of the
file
and
you can
set up
here
a trigger
single trigger
that can be
started manually
stopped manually
or
can be
triggered by
the cable
so the
program node
itself
the code
that we
define
and then
you can
just
perform the
log but
right now
we cannot
do that
anyway
along with
all the
analysis
windows that
we have
just seen
as we were
mentioning
before
canalizer
allows you
also to
stimulate
and interact
with the
live
communication
in the
example
cambus
or
limbus
or whatever
communication
bus it is
that
you are
interacting
with
using the
analyzer
online
mooc
configuration
for example
a few of
the
means that
you can use
in order to
interact
with
a
real
communication
whatever
it is
is
the
click here
with the
right
bottom
can
practice
generator
let's
double click
here
you've got
this whole
new
blank
window
right
bottom
add
frame
from the
database
once again
we are starting
from the
dbc
file that
we upload
in the
analyzer
we can
add
specific
cammessage
selected
client
you can see
it just appeared
background
but we can also
add
a whole list
of
cammessages
here
this
column here
we've got the
name
cammessage
all the
list
we
added
the
trigger
that we want
to use
in order
to
send
that we
want to send
that specific
message
for example
we can
manually
send it
once again
i'm not running
online
mode
but
we can
manually send it
clicking on here
or we can
for example
send it
periodically
so without having
to do that
manually
and the cycle
time
reported here
is the one
that was
extracted from
the dbc
file when
we selected
an important
year
this
cammessage
or it
can be also
done
manually
and we can
also
link
the
transmission
of
disc and
message
according to a
system variable
that can be
defined
in the
program
node
on the
other side
node
with defining
which messages
we want to
send
ones that are
already
present in the
dbc
or as we
have seen
before
messages
that we
added
in on
radio
exists
in dbc
um
we can
find
how to
send them
we can
change
the values
of the
can signals
inside of
these
of those
kind of
messages
for example
inside
the cmfd2
we can
decide
for example
here
maybe
is that
opens
the bottom
left
side
of the
window
the values
of
i don't know
if you're
records
right now
physical value
by dbc
by default value
is equal to
normal
if you will
and running
the analyzer in online mode
we could
basically change
that these
can signal
inside of
these
can
message
otherwise
and we can
do that
basically for
all the
can
signal
inside of
all the
can messages
that we
add here
and this
is uh
let me say
a method
that can
be used
when we want
for example
to send
messages
that are not
sent in the
real
can bus
that we are
working on
but
when we want
to
some messages
that we are
creating
let me say
x
novel
because if
we want to
modify a
message
or a
signal
which is
already
sent
that can
bus
by a
real
electronic
control unit
we cannot
use the
this
block
here
we can
interactive
generator
block
because we
would just
overlap the
message that
we are
sending to
the one
that is
sent by
the real
issue
if we
want to
instead
perform
sort of
gateway
and i
suggest
to go
to the
dedicated
lesson
in the
academy
for this
part here
regarding
how the
interactive
generator
block
or the
kpop
program
nodes can
be used
and when
they should
be used
for testing
we can
use the
program
node here
so always
right bottom
program node
double click
and right now
it asks us
to select
an already
available
capable
program
for example
i've already
got one
the gateway
so i just
uploaded this
file
and
just wait a few
seconds
that
file is
being uploaded
opened by
canalizer
you will be able
to modify
for example
the manual
code
according to
the action
that you
want to
do
for example
this was
a code
people
code
written
in order
to perform
a gateway
amongst
one
ECU
under testing
and all
the other
ECUs
in the
cat bus
but i suggest
you to go
through the
dedicated
lesson
for this
specific
window
regarding the
data
visualization
another
very useful
thing that
can be used
is
the panel
feature
that you
can find
here in
tools
panel designer
so basically
the panels
are just
graphical
elements
that you
can use
in order
to modify
or to
visualize
can
single
values
or
system
variable
values
and
they can
be
very easily
created
this one is
a new
panel
they just
created
decided
for example
that's
this list
here
to the right
let's drag
and drop
drop
i don't
know
let's
see
a bar
or
meter
progress bar
and
what we want
for example
to see
here
is the
visual representation
i don't know
vehicle speed
we just did
for the graph
we click here
and drag it
here
in order
to link
that cash
signal to
the two
panels
that we
just
created
when you
select a
panel
you can
right
click
and go
on
show
properties
in order
to for
example
define
the minimum
and maximum
value
of that
panel
you can
choose
one
display
on the
value
where you
want
to be
to be seen
and
let's do that
also for
this other panel
the meter
here
so let's
change
for example
the angles
it's very
useful
from
a visual
when you say
final view
value range
for the
vehicle speed
level
to the
maximum
right now
if you click
the meter
you will see
that it is
linked to
the can
signal
vehicle
speed
vso
sig
link
not link
but
and signal
vehicle speed
included in the
break of
mutual
method
and the
same
for the
progress
bar
so you
save
it
browse
and here it is
if you run
analyzer in off the mode as you were doing
or if you run
run analyzer in off the mode as you were doing
my bad
let me add it again
this is a
x
node
part of it we just create again let's open one and create together this one
one
right here
so if you run analyzer
you will see that it was changing according to the
vehicle speed value
if you want to have a comparison for example you can add here
the graph window so you can compare when you will see for example here
vehicle speed evolving
when you see the panel
values evolving
so it's just another way of representing
let me say
can signal or system variables value
the only last feature that
you could
let's say dive deeper into it
would be
the program node and
can interactive
generator block
but
as i was mentioning you before
there is a dedicated lesson
for
that topic
so i would suggest you to go
through
that one
and
that's it
that is just
what we just had together was a
high level
lesson
we say
very basic regarding analyzer usage
so
i will be available for any verification
needed
i will be available to answer to any
all of your questions
and
i
just
nothing else
i will be available for
for anything so
enjoy your day
have a
have a good day
see you